Guide to the Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers vvb
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne papers
1772-1983
1910-1960
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1882-1975
Browne, Maurice, 1881-1955
vvb
50 Linear Feet 39 boxes, 3 oversize boxes, 90 bound volumes, 7 drawers
The Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne Papers document their personal and professional lives together. The papers are also an important source for American and British theater history.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: Correspondence Writings Theatrical Work Samurai Press Personal and Family Photographs Artwork Scrapbooks Printed Material Realia
Biographical / Historical
Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg (1882-1975) Actress; puppeteer. Born in Battle Creek, Mich., Oct. 8, 1882; University of Michigan, A.B.; married Mauric Browne in Chicago, June 1, 1912. From 1905 acted in a variety of modern plays; assistant director and actress in Chicago Little Theatre Co., 1912-13. Avid supporter of women's suffrage.
In the United States, the artistic puppet revival was largely inspired by Ellen Van Volkenburg at the Chicago Little Theatre with productions that included A Midsummer Night's Dream in 1916. She later directed plays for Tony Sarg, who became the most important influence in American puppetry.
"Browne, Ellen Van Volkenburg." Woman's Who's Who of America: A Biographical Dictionary of Contemporary Women of the United States and Canada, 1914-1915.
Browne, Maurice (1881-1955) Actor, dramatist, and theatre manager. Born in 1881 and educated in England, founded the Little Theatre movement by the establishment in 1912 of the Chicago Little Theatre. In 1920 he was directing on Broadway, and in 1927 he made his first appearance in London, as Adolf in Strindberg's The Creditors.
In 1929, he took over the management of the Savoy Theatre and presented there with remarkable success R. C. Sherriff's war play Journey's End, himself playing Lieutenant Raleigh. In the following year he produced Othello with Paul Robeson, playing Iago himself. He retired at the end of 1939.
"Browne, Maurice." The Concise Oxford Companion to the Theatre. Ed. Phyllis Hartnoll and Peter Found. Oxford University Press, 1996.
Scope and Contents
The Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne Papers document their personal and professional lives together. The papers are also an important source for American and British theater history.
Correspondence – Extensively documents the personal and professional activities of MB and EVV – Letters to their families, to each other, correspondence to/from other people connected with the theatre – Major correspondents include: Mary Aldis, Dorothy Crawford, Cyril Edwards, Dorothy and Leonard Elmirst, Arthur Davison Ficke, Wilfrid Wilson Gibson, Alexander Greene, Harold Monro, John Cowper Powys, R.C. Stewart, Charles Erskine Scott Wood – Also correspondence about Henry Morley, related to MB's attempted revision of Morley's A First Sketch of English Literature
Writings – Typescripts, annotations, notes, galleys, etc. – MB's autobiography, Too Late to Lament; his plays, including multiple drafts of titles such as The King of the Jews, The Mother of Gregory, and Wings over Europe; prose, including Recollections of Rupert Brooke; and poetry – EVV plays, including Ameriga Vespucci, The American, The Queen's Keys; her prose – Works by others
Theatrical Work – Companies and associations such as Chicago Little Theatre, Cornish School, Maurice Browne Ltd. - contracts, correspondence, financial records, meeting minutes, programs, scripts – Playbills - productions associated with Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, divided into United States and Great Britain; other productions – Printing plates of images and text used for Chicago Little Theatre materials such as playbills, etc. – Promptbooks for many of their plays, including published versions of the plays marked with cuts and edited versions EVV used in readings she gave – Puppets - small amount of material related to puppet productions
Samurai Press – Maurice Browne's project with Harold Monro – Correspondence, business records, several manuscripts, scrapbook, clippings, etc.
Personal and Family – Personal materials related to Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg, including correspondence about their engagement, divorce, etc. – EVV's 39 journals covering 1910-1966 – Papers of other family members - Frances Anna Browne, F.H. Browne (MB's father - his papers, dismissal as headmaster, suicide), Edward Stanley Browne, F.W. Mercer (manuscripts he hand lettered and illuminated) – Family papers - Browne family, Neligan family, indentures on vellum
Photographs – Have been organized into groupings by subject – Family and Friends (roman numerals signify subject groupings - legacy from earlier cataloging) - Many photographs of EVV and MB, their families, travel photographs (MB went to India as a young man), Molly Underwood, John Cowper Powys, Arthur Davison Ficke, Mary Aldis, Marjorie Morris, other friends – London and New York I and II - organized by title of play - production/cast photographs (see both categories - not intermingled) - many from Journey's End production – Chicago Little Theatre, Cornish School, and Carmel - organized by title of play - many from Trojan Women – Associates - actors, guest artists, others associated with them
Artwork – Costume and stage designs for various productions (organized by last name of artist when known) - separate section for Othello – Miscellaneous art works - including portraits, woodcuts, watercolors, prints, sketches (organized by last name of artist when known)
Scrapbooks – contain photographs, clippings, programs (some not represented elsewhere in the collection) – some appear to have been created by professional clipping services – document Maurice Browne's parents, their early lives, public appearances, theater reviews, etc.
Printed Material – clippings, topical files
Realia – three breastplates and leather pouch worn by Paul Robeson in Othello, 1930 – puppet made of paper and bamboo – small plaster head (appears to have broken off something)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Little theater movement; Theater -- United States -- 20th century.; Chicago Little Theatre Company; Cornish School (Seattle, Wash.: 1920-1955); Samurai Press
- Correspondence
  - Maurice Browne correspondence
    - Early correspondence, 1902-1909 (Box 1)
    - Early correspondence: Buddh Gayā papers, 1907 (Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - To his parents, ca. 1887-1894; 5 folders (Box 1)
      - To his mother
        - Letters, 1895-1923; 26 folders (Box 1)
        - Letters, 1924-1934; 6 folders (Box 2)
        - Inscription (photocopy), undated; 1 items (Box 2)
      - Van Volkenburg, Ellen
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1921-1948 and undated; 23 folders (Box 2)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1949-1953; 6 folders (Box 3)
      - By Molly Underwood, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
      - To others, 3 folders
        - Adam, Ronald, 1939 (Box 3)
        - Aiken-Smith, Pearl (Box 3)
        - Albery, Bronson (Box 3)
        - Brown, Gilmor (Box 3)
        - Christian, Bertram (Box 3)
        - Clewe, J. F. (Box 3)
        - Creagh, James Vandeleur (Box 3)
        - Drama League of America (Box 3)
        - Ensor, Aubrey (Box 3)
        - Freakins, William B., 1935 (Box 3)
        - Gollancz, Victor, 1951 and undated (Box 3)
        - Hart, T. C. (Box 3)
        - Head, Cloyd (Box 3)
        - Herndon, Richard (Box 3)
        - Huebsch, [Benjamin] (Box 3)
        - Joseph, Nannie, 1953 (Box 3)
        - Keen, Herbert F., 1953 (Box 3)
        - Langner, Lawrence, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
        - Leigh, W. Colston, 1935 (Box 3)
        - Leith-Hay-Clarke, Norman, 1943 (Box 3)
        - Martin, John Joseph, 1943 (Box 3)
        - Murray, Gilbert, 1943 (Box 3)
        - National Council of Social Service, 1941 (Box 3)
        - Newman, Chaim, 1943 (Box 3)
        - Hurburt O'Hara, Frank, 1936 (Box 3)
        - Ould, Hermon, 1929 (Box 3)
        - Paxinou, Katina, 1939 (Box 3)
        - Pryde, James Ferrier, 1930 (Box 3)
        - Rice, Warner Grenelle, 1946 (Box 3)
        - Shove, John, 1951 (Box 3)
        - Springer, Ada E., 1926 (Box 3)
        - Urmey, Edythe Beatrice, 1931 (Box 3)
        - Van Volkenburg, Frank Hoyt ("Pater"), 1925 (Box 3)
        - Van Volkenburg, Juliet (Cooper), ca. 1920-1955 (Box 3)
        - Widtsoe, John Andreas, 1936 (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous Letters, 1912-1950 and undated (Box 3)
  - Ellen Van Volkenburg correspondence
    - Early correspondence, 1903-1908; 1 folders
      - Burnham, Clara Louise (Root), 1908 (Box 3)
      - D---?, 1904 (Box 3)
      - de Prout, Edward P., 1903 (Box 3)
      - Dickey, Paul, 1903 and undated (Box 3)
      - Ed ("T---")?, 1904 (Box 3)
      - J., E. B., 1901 (Box 3)
      - Melville, Belle Watson, 1907 (Box 3)
      - Nobble, Edna Chaffee, 1906 (Box 3)
      - Poppo, 1904-1926 (Box 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - To Her Parents, 1913-1930; 9 folders (Box 3)
      - To Her Mother, 1931-1937; 6 folders (Box 3)
      - Browne, Maurice
        - Letters, 1910; 4 folders (Box 3)
        - Letters, 1910-1940; 30 folders (Box 4)
        - Letters, 1941-1949 and undated; 6 folders (Box 5)
      - Browne, Francis Anna Nelligan, 1911-1931 and undated; 3 folders (Box 5)
      - To Others, 2 folders
        - Arendt, Arthur, 1938 (Box 5)
        - Brighton, Hilda, 1958 (Box 5)
        - Burr, Mrs., 1937 (Box 5)
          Scope and Contents
          Includes incoming and outgoing correspondence.
        - Burrell, John, 1949 (Box 5)
        - Commins, Saxe, 1936 (Box 5)
        - Cornish, Nellie C., 1956 (Box 5)
        - Degener, Claire S., 1958 (Box 5)
        - "Elena", 1939 (Box 5)
        - Entrekin, Knowles, undated (Box 5)
        - Ewing, Rose D., 1958 (Box 5)
          Includes part of a travel diary.
        - Green, Mr., 1937 (Box 5)
        - Gwatkin, Fred A. S., 1932 (Box 5)
        - Houghton, Norris, 1957 (Box 5)
        - Howell, Miriam Olive, 1934 (Box 5)
        - Marks, Seymour, 1934 (Box 5)
        - [Mavor, Osborne H.] and Bridie, James, [1932] (Box 5)
        - Registrar of Copyright, undated (Box 5)
        - Ridgeway, Peter, 1934 (Box 5)
        - Rosenfield, Sybil M., 1956 (Box 5)
        - Saroyan, William, 1936 (Box 5)
        - Scofield, Paul, 1958 (Box 5)
        - Thorndike, Sybil, 1934 (Box 5)
        - Tripp, Ruth, 1937 (Box 5)
        - Tyler, Carolyn D., 1937 (Box 5)
        - Wanamaker, Sam, 1958 (Box 5)
        - Letters and Notes to Various and Unidentified Correspondents, 1936-1952 and undated (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous Letters, 1937-1958 (Box 5)
    - Incoming correspondence
      - A-Z, 2 folders
        - Bahr, A. W., undated (Box 5)
        - Battle, Helen S., undated (Box 5)
        - Beck, Mrs., ca. 1956 and undated (Box 5)
          Regarding Nellie Cornish
        - [Chamblis?], Erica, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Cheshire, Harold, undated (Box 5)
        - Cohen, Madeline, 1932 (Box 5)
        - [Cornish, Nellie], 1955 (Box 5)
        - Dommelen, Diane van, undated (Box 5)
        - Franklin High School teacher, 1925 (Box 5)
        - Gellendré Theatre Studio students, [1955] (Box 5)
        - Goffin, Peter, undated (Box 5)
        - [Hartley?], Eleir, 1937 or 1957 (Box 5)
        - Storie, Archibald Henderson, undated (Box 5)
        - Hollingsworth family, undated (Box 5)
        - [Hurst?], Phillis, undated (Box 5)
        - Husby, Ruth Madgadelen, undated (Box 5)
        - Keen, Helen, undated (Box 5)
        - [McGaw?], Emma, 1955 (Box 5)
        - [McLorn?], Hugh, undated (Box 5)
        - Nakis, Gertrude, ca. 1955? (Box 5)
        - Pearce, Dorothy, and Gould, Evelyn, 1950 (Box 5)
          To Maurice Browne.
        - Richards family, 1949 and undated (Box 5)
        - Richardson, Reginald C., 1958 (Box 5)
          To F. A. Browne or Ellen Van Volkenburg?
        - Sandford, Jillian, undated (Box 5)
        - Skin, Martin?, 1946 (Box 5)
          To "Dear Sir."
        - Smith, Sue Carrington, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
        - Stage Door Canteen Senior Hostess Committee, 1945 (Box 5)
        - [Straus], Ralph, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Toyne, Gabriel, undated (Box 5)
        - V., B., 1955 (Box 5)
        - Week, Anna, undated (Box 5)
      - Christmas greetings, 1969 and undated (Box 5)
        Correspondents: Sauter, R. H. (nephew of John Galsworthy) Sims, Alistair ___, Dorothy
      - Correspondence and manuscripts from friends, 1915-1970 (Box 5)
      - Curator's notes, undated (Box 5)
      - Telegrams to Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1930 and undated (Box 5)
      - Unidentified correspondents, 1 folders
        - Adolph and Zora, 1938 (Box 5)
        - Anna, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
        - Barbara, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Beryl, undated (Box 5)
        - Bobby, [1955?] (Box 5)
        - Byron and Doro, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Caroline, undated (Box 5)
          To Mrs. T. H. (or F. H.) van Volkenburg ("Etta").
        - Cecile, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Cornelia, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Deirdre, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Diana, 1960 (Box 5)
          Removed from a copy of Bonham-Carter's The Story of Dartington.
        - Dorothy, 1928, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
          To Mrs. Frank Van Volkenburg (1928) and to Ellen Van Volkenburg (1955-1956).
        - Edward, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Eloise, undated (Box 5)
        - Eloise and Johnny, undated (Box 5)
        - Fred, [1955] (Box 5)
        - Gladys, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Harold, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Irene and Susie, 1953 (Box 5)
        - "Lambie", 1941 (Box 5)
          Dated at Dartington Hall, Totnes.
        - Laurence, 1955-1956 (Box 5)
          To Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg.
        - Louise, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Maisie, 1935 (Box 5)
        - Margaret, 1955 [and 1935?] (Box 5)
        - Marjorie and Enid, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Martha, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Muna, [ca. 1955] (Box 5)
        - Oliver, 1953 (Box 5)
        - Pauline, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Peter, 1960 (Box 5)
        - Phil, 1939 (Box 5)
        - R., undated (Box 5)
        - Rena, undated (Box 5)
        - Roland, undated (Box 5)
          To "Mother".
        - Ruth, 1969 (Box 5)
        - Tookie, 1955 (Box 5)
        - Wyatt, 1931 (Box 5)
        - Anonymous, 1928 and undated (Box 5)
          Regarding Unknown Warrior.
        - Anonymous, undated (Box 5)
          With a group of cards to "Mummy".
        - Anonymous and unidentified, 1946-1958 and undated (Box 5)
  - Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne correspondence
    - Incoming correspondence
      - "Letters from Group", August 1948 (Box 5)
      - Various correspondents, 1919-1930 (Box 5)
    - Ellen Van Volkenburg and Maurice Browne's notes on correspondence, undated (Box 5)
  - Name File
    - Abercrombie, Lascelles, 1913-1930 (Box 5)
    - Ackland, Rodney (Box 5)
    - Adam, Ronald (Box 5)
    - Adams, Joseph Quincy (Box 5)
    - Addams, Jane (Box 5)
    - Agate, James Evershed (Box 5)
    - Agate, May (Box 5)
    - Ahlefeldt-Laurvig, Preben (Box 5)
    - Aiken-Smith, Pearle (Box 5)
    - Aikins, Carroll, 1919-1925 (Box 5)
    - Ainley, Henry (Box 5)
    - Akins, Zoë (Box 5)
    - Albery, Sir Bronson (Box 5)
    - Aldis, Mary (Reynolds)
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Barry, Griffin (Box 5)
        - Browne, Maurice; Ellen Van Volkenburg; and Mrs. Juliet Van Volkenburg (Box 5)
      - Documents, 1916 and undated (Box 5)
      - Writings
        - The Five Who Pushed On, undated (Box 5)
        - The Grasshopper, undated (Box 5)
          Translated and adapted from the French of E. Grenet-Dancourt.
        - The Hangman's Daughter, Act II, undated (Box 5)
        - The Messenger of Sleep, undated (Box 5)
        - The Monk and the Hangman's Daughter, undated (Box 5)
        - Poetry, undated (Box 5)
        - Seven Sad Sonnets, 1922 (Box 5)
        - "Wonder", 1922 (Box 5)
    - Allen, John (Box 5)
      Student at Cambridge.
    - Allgood, Sara (Box 5)
    - Allshorn, W. M. (Box 5)
    - Ames, Winthrop (Box 5)
    - Ampthill, Arthur Oliver Viliers Russel, 2nd baron (Box 5)
    - Anand, Mulk Raj (Box 5)
    - Anderson, Celia M. (Box 5)
    - Anderson, Garland (Box 5)
    - Anderson, Judith (Box 5)
    - Anglin, Margaret (Box 5)
    - Anspacher, Louis Kaufman (Box 5)
    - Arbach, Vera (Box 5)
    - Archer, William (Box 5)
    - Arent, Arthur (Box 5)
    - Arkell, Reginald (Box 5)
    - Arliss, George (Box 5)
    - Armfield, Anne Constance (Smedley) (Box 5)
    - Armfield, Maxwell (Box 5)
    - Armour, Jonathan Ogden (Box 5)
    - Armstrong, John (Box 5)
    - Armstrong, William (Box 5)
    - Arnaud, Yvonne Germaine (Box 5)
    - Arntzenius, Constance and Peronne (Box 5)
    - Arthur, Sir George Compton Archibald, baronet (Box 5)
    - Ashcroft, Dame Peggy (Box 5)
    - Ashford, Kathleen (Box 5)
    - Ashmole, Bernard (Box 5)
    - Astor, Nancy Witcher Langhorne, viscountess (Box 5)
    - Aylmer, Felix (Box 5)
    - Aynesworth, Allan (Box 5)
    - Ayscough, Florence (Wheelock) (Box 5)
    - Baldwin, Oliver (Box 5)
    - Babcock, Conrad Stanton (Box 5)
    - Baker, George Pierce (Box 5)
    - Balcon, Sir Michael (Box 5)
    - Baring, Hon. Maurice (Box 5)
    - Barnes, Cyril B. (Box 5)
    - Barnet, I. (Box 5)
    - Barrett, Mitzi (Box 5)
    - Barry, Griffin (Box 5)
    - Barton, Lionel H. (Box 5)
    - Batchelder, Majorie Hope (Box 5)
    - Bax, Clifford
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, and others (Box 5)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, and Browne, Maurice (Box 5)
      - Incoming correspondence, undated (Box 5)
    - Baxter, Arthur Beverley (Box 5)
    - Baxter, Jane (Box 5)
    - Baylis, Lilian Mary (Box 5)
    - Beal, John (Box 5)
    - Belfrage, Bruce (Box 5)
    - Bell, Robert (Box 5)
    - Bellerby, Frances (Parker) (Box 5)
    - Ben-Ami, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Bennett, Arnold (Box 5)
    - Bennett, Dorothy Cheston (Box 5)
    - Benson, Sir Francis Robert (Box 5)
    - Berger, Margareta (Hamerschlag) (Box 5)
    - Berkley-Hill, Samuel T. (Box 5)
    - Biddle, Edmund Randolph (Box 5)
    - Bing, Al (Box 5)
    - Birch, Frank (Box 5)
    - Biro, Golan (Box 5)
    - Biro, Lajos (Box 5)
    - Bispham, David Scull (Box 5)
    - Bjöorkman, Edwin August (Box 5)
    - Blagden, Minnie (Box 5)
    - Blair, Mary A. (Box 5)
    - Blau, Béla (Box 5)
    - Blinn, Holbrook (Box 5)
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1971 (Box 5)
      To Ellen Van Volkenburg
    - Bloch, Bertram (Box 5)
    - Blum, Jerome S. (Box 5)
    - Bodenheim, Maxwell (Box 5)
    - Bohlman, Edgar Lemoine (Box 5)
    - Bojer, Johan (Box 5)
    - Bohn, Adolph (Box 5)
    - Bondi, Beulah (Box 5)
    - Bonstell, Jessie (Box 5)
    - Bottomley, Gordon (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice (Box 5)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 5)
        - Gibson, W. W. (Box 5)
    - Boughton, Rutland (Box 5)
    - Bourdet, Edouard (Box 5)
    - Boxall, G. (Box 5)
    - Bradley, Dorothy (Box 5)
    - Brady, William A. (Box 5)
    - Bragdon, Claude Fayette (Box 5)
    - Brandon-Thomas, Amy Marguerite (Box 5)
    - Bridges-Adams, William (Box 5)
    - Bridgewater, Leslie (Box 5)
    - Brighten, Hilda (Box 5)
    - Brittain, Vera May (Box 5)
    - Bromley, Dorothy (Box 5)
    - Brook, Clive (Box 5)
    - Brooke, Rupert
      - Correspondence, 1908-1957 (Box 6)
        Photocopies.
      - Manuscripts, correspondence, and photographs, 1914-1915 (Box 6)
        Includes dealer description.
    - Brown, Alice
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1912-1921 (Box 6)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen, 1917-1920 (Box 6)
        - Van Volkenburg, Juliet (Cooper), [1920?] (Box 6)
    - Brown, Gilmor (Box 6)
    - Browne, Ellen Janson
      - Works
        - If We Shadows, 1925 (Box 6)
        - Poem, undated (Box 6)
    - Browne, Frances Anna (Neligan), 1925-1933 (Box 6)
      To Maurice Browne and Ellen Van Volkenburg
    - Browne, Francesca ("Frankie")
      - Correspondence
        - Letters and poems to Maurice Browne, 1940-1947 (Box 6)
        - To Ellen Van Volkenburg, 1928-1949 (Box 6)
        - To others, 1928 (Box 6)
      - Poems, ca. 1912-1947 (Box 6)
    - Browne, Harper G. (Box 6)
    - Browne, Maurice Ivar (Praxy), 1937-1938 (Box 6)
      Works: Poems.
    - Brueger, Ellen (Box 6)
    - Brutton, H. L. (Box 6)
    - Buchanan, Andrew (Box 6)
    - Buckley, Doris (Box 6)
    - Buckmaster, John (Box 6)
    - Burrell, John (Box 6)
    - Bush, Jean M. (Box 6)
    - Butcher, Fanny (Box 6)
    - Bynner, Witter
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice, 1936-1950 (Box 6)
        - Underwood, Molly, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
    - Byrne, Muriel St. Clare (Box 6)
    - Callahan, Kenneth (Box 6)
    - Cameron, C. F. (Box 6)
    - Cammell, Charles Richard (Box 6)
    - Carpenter, Edward (Box 6)
    - Cary, Lucien (Box 6)
    - Casson, John (Box 6)
    - Casson, Lewis (Box 6)
    - Cecil of Chelwood, Robert Gascoyne-Cecil, viscount (Box 6)
    - Chadwick, Joyce (Box 6)
    - Chamberlain, Neville (Box 6)
    - Chekhov, Michael (Box 6)
    - Cherry, Jeanne (Yeats) (Box 6)
    - Christian, Bertram (Box 6)
    - Church, Peggy Pond (Box 6)
    - Clarke, Dora (Harrow) (Box 6)
    - Claudel, Paul (Box 6)
    - Clements, John (Box 6)
    - Cleverdon, Douglas (Box 6)
    - Clewe, J. F. (Box 6)
    - Clift, A. F. (Box 6)
    - Clive, Colin (Box 6)
    - Clough, M. Parnelia (Box 6)
    - Cochran, Charles Blake (Box 6)
    - Collins, Francis (Box 6)
    - Commins, Saxe (Box 6)
    - Cone, Arthur Lambert (Box 6)
    - Connelly, Marcus Cook (Box 6)
    - Conroy, Frank (Box 6)
    - Constanduros, Mabel (Box 6)
    - Coomaraswamy, Ananda Kentish (Box 6)
    - Cooper, G. Melville (Box 6)
    - Copeau, Jacques
      - Outgoing correspondence
        - Browne, Maurice (Box 6)
        - Van Volkenburg, Ellen (Box 6)
    - Copley, John (Box 6)
    - Cornell, Katharine (Box 6)
    - Cornish, Nellie Centennial (Box 6)
    - Cotsworth, Staats Jennings (Box 6)
    - Cottie, Nic (Box 6)
    - Cowan, Marjory (Box 6)
    - Coward, Noel Pierce (Box 6)
    - Cowl, Jane (Box 6)
    - Cowles, Thomas (Box 6)
    - Cox, Lesley (Box 6)
    - Cox, Philip (Box 6)
    - Craig, Edward Gordon (Box 6)
    - Crawford, Dorothy
      - Correspondence with Ellen Van Volkenburg
        - General, 1938 and undated (Box 6)
        - Letters about "Kip", 1946 and undated (Box 6)
          These letters pertain to Kip, a play that Crawford and Van Volkenburg wrote together.
      - Writings: "Kip"
        Co-written with Ellen van Volkenburg. Multiple typescript drafts.
        - "Original Draft", undated (Box 6)
          Holograph.
        - "First Draft", undated (Box 6)
        - First Draft, undated (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous brochures and correspondence, undated (Box 6)
    - Creagh, James Vandeleur (Box 6)
    - Crocker, Bosworth, pseud. (Box 6)
    - Cromer, Rowland, Thomas Baring, 2d earl of (Box 6)
    - Cummins, Phyllis Deborah (Box 6)
    - Curtiss, Charles Chauncey (Box 6)
    - Cushman, Catharine ("Kip") (Box 6)
    - Cyon, François Lafitte (Box 6)
    - Daby-Hunter, Zillah (Box 6)
    - Daly, Arnold (Box 6)
    - Darlington, William Aubrey (Box 6)
    - Davies, Frederich (Box 6)
      Biographical / Historical
      Of Cheshire, England.
    - Davis, Hallie (Ferguson) Flanagan (Box 6)
    - Davis, Ruth Helen (Box 6)
    - Dawson, Oswald Royal (Box 6)
    - Dean, Basil (Box 6)
    - Dearmer, Geoffrey (Box 6)
    - De Casalis, Jeanne (Box 6)
    - De Friston, Adrian Francis Annesley (Box 6)
    - Degener, Claire S. (Box 6)
    - De La Mare, Walter John (Box 6)
    - Dell, Floyd (Box 6)
    - de Roulet, Marie Antoinette (Box 6)
    - Dettinger, Alma (Box 6)
    - Dickinson, Patric (Box 6)
    - Digby, C. W. (Box 6)